[Music]
Hello, everyone.
TDSW YouTube Channel.
This will be the seventh episode of Getting started with GLSL on TouchDesigner.
Thank you for watching!
This time, the one you're watching right now.
I'm going to make this kind of kaleidoscope effect.
Let me first introduce you to something called ISF
Originally, it was part of a software feature called VDMX.
You can write effects based on GLSL
this is called
What we're going to do this time.
First of all, this introduction to the ISF
Next, select the kaleidoscope in the ISF sample and use
We'll make this work in TouchDesigner
Finally, I used these ISFs.
I'd like to talk about how to study effects.
So let's get to it.
As I mentioned earlier, ISF is a part of VDMX.
VDMX is VJ software for Mac and
You can write your own Shader in ISF
You can use it in VDMX
ISF has an editor for the Mac, too.
There is also an editor that works in the browser
That's what this page is all about.
This is the top page.
This way, you can tweak the parameters in the browser and
They can change the effects and support you.
You can change the image or use your own webcam
I can even put in a video.
View a list of people with this username VIDVOX
These VIDVOX people.
I mean, these are the people who make VDMX.
They are, um... these ISF files.
I'm releasing it under the MIT license.
Select a file to be converted in TouchDesigner from among these
By the way, here's the GitHub page with the ISF files
Here's what's actually up in your browser right now
The Shader file has been uploaded!
Come back to this page.
I will be using this Kaleidoscope.fs
I'd like to use this Kaleidoscope.fs
I got this screen.
First of all... here on the right.
There are parameters.
There's a code on the left side.
It will be this kind of thing.
Fix the code.
You can also update it in your browser
This kind of interactive environment in the browser is a great way to get the most out of
Well, there are a few things.
This will be one of them.
Actually, the center point of this one isn't moving properly.
We'll get to this later.
We'll fix it in TouchDesigner.
Now I'd like to take this code to TouchDesigner
Open the code.
copy
If you copy it.
Place GLSL Top in TouchDesigner
Input images from Movie File In
Not flowers this time, but a drum.
I'll take it.
I'll get you a link.
Open the Shader in the editor again
Here's what happened.
I'm going to copy this first.
At the top are the properties
This is the one used by the ISF only
This doesn't particularly affect me because it's been commented out.
There's a constant here.
Since there are two main functions, the
I'm going to need this copy.
We'll put them inside.
If you do this, you'll get a lot of errors here.
We're going to have to crush these one by one.
First.
I don't want this.
The output ends in gl_FragColor.
Change the way you do things in TouchDesigner
Let's start with this.
First of all, I'm going to take all of these properties up here.
We will declare it as a uniform variable
inputImage
Let's just skip this one for a second.
sides, which are of type float, and
Let's call this the SIDES
If you do this, the error with the sides in it will disappear
Next, we'll put in an angle.
The error is also disappearing again.
slidex
It's also called slidey.
It's called center.
There's something called point2d that I'm not familiar with.
This can be handled by vec2
The number of errors has decreased significantly.
There are a lot of variables that are a little unfamiliar to me.
I'd like to check this out on the ISF website
First of all, it's called RENDERSIZE.
I'd like to look into this.
Here's the page with the ISF specs
If you search for RENDERSIZE here
The vec2 RENDERSIZE is
Since it says it's the size of the renderings.
I'm going to put in 1280x720 later.
First, let me make one declaration here.
Is it easier to see it this way?
I searched for isf_FragNormCoord and found
This one is also automatically declared by the
It's a number between [0, 0] and [1, 1].
That's what it says.
This is.
In TouchDesigner's Fragment Shader, I used to use
It can be replaced by vUV.st
So I'm going to replace the value in here with vUV.st
Like this.
I think that reduces the errors again.
I'm going to search for IMG_NORM_PIXEL this time.
Basically, it's something that takes pixels when you use an image or something.
since it is the case that
It is used as an alternative to texture2D or texture2DRect
This texture2D or something like that is called texture in TouchDesigner. Yes.
This one. It's a viable substitute.
Furthermore, this inputImage is a
It's about this incoming image.
In TouchDesigner.
This sTD2DInputs[0] can be replaced by
IMG_NORM_PIXEL as texture
Replace the inputImage with this sTD2DInputs[0]
It came out this way.
Then the error is gone.
If there are no errors in this state, the declaration of this uniform will be
You can load in this Load Uniform Names
I think each variable was automatically entered.
First of all, these values of
I'm going to put in a little bit of the default value.
Default 6 for sides.
Angle defaults to 0.
1280x720 for RENDERSIZE
That's the same pixels as this image.
Next, slidey and slidex default to 0
This one has a zero and a zero.
It's the center position.
I'm trying to put this in the middle.
Enter something like 640x360.
Then I think we'd have a screen like this now.
I think this already looks pretty good.
The angle.
I'm going to use CHOP to move it around.
Make the screen wide once.
First, put in the LFO CHOP.
Add a Null.
Put this at the angle
It's ridiculously fast.
I'm going to try to slow this down.
Frequency is set to 0.1
It's like this.
It still feels a little fast.
Let's say 0.02.
It's like this.
This is what it looked like.
Now it works like the first one I showed you.
I think it's a kaleidoscope effect.
I'm not going to explain this code in a bit this time.
You can play with these parameters and color correct them.
And you know what?
Please take a look at the other effects if you're interested.
License-wise, if it was made by this VIDVOX.
I don't think there's a problem with that.
You know, I've seen some of his other work, but if you look at it.
I'm sure you'll have many ideas.
It's not just the browser version.
This desktop version is also available
I thought it was just the Mac version, but it looks like there's a Windows beta out as well.
Try it out if you're interested.
This ISF page.
Open each ISF and if there are any variables you haven't seen before, you can use
Take a look at the specifications page I mentioned earlier.
Just the part about using Buffer.
It might be a bit of a pain in the ass.
The rest of it isn't that hard.
I think it would be an easy conversion.
We will talk about Buffer in TouchDesigner soon!
That's it for this one.
About twice a month at TDSW.
We're running live streaming workshops on the weekend.
Tickets are available through Petix and Eventbrite!
We also use Patreon
There are currently three plans available
You can find these links in the video overview section of the video
Check it out if you'd like.
So thank you for watching.
If you like it, please subscribe to our channel!
goodbye
[Music]